<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Rare Quran Manuscript</title>
            </titleStmt>
        </fileDesc> 
    </teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="edition" subtype="diplomatic" ana="b1">
                <figure>
                    <graphic url="assets/image0.jpg" mimeType="image/jpeg"/>
                    <figDesc>
                        Holy Quran, handwritten.
                        Very old, possibly over 280 years. No date of writing is indicated. Its cover is old, and the pages are bound with threads.
                        Rare. 
                    </figDesc>
                </figure>

                <div>
                 <h2>Transliteration (Arabic)</h2>
                <p xml:lang="ar">
                    سورة البقرة مدنية وهي مئتان وثمانون
                    بسم الله الرحمن الرحيم
                    الٓمٓ ذَٰلِكَ ٱلۡكِتَٰبُ لَا رَيۡبَۛ فِيهِۛ هُدٗى لِّلۡمُتَّقِينَ ٱلَّذِينَ يُؤۡمِنُونَ بِٱلۡغَيۡبِ وَيُقِيمُونَ ٱلصَّلَوٰةَ وَمِمَّا رَزَقۡنَٰهُمۡ يُنفِقُونَ وَٱلَّذِينَ يُؤۡمِنُونَ بِمَآ أُنزِلَ إِلَيۡكَ وَمَآ أُنزِلَ مِن قَبۡلِكَ وَبِٱلۡأٓخِرَةِ هُمۡ يُوقِنُونَ أُوْلَٰٓئِكَ عَلَىٰ هُدٗى مِّن رَّبِّهِمۡۖ وَأُوْلَٰٓئِكَ هُمُ ٱلۡمُفۡلِحُونَ
                    وست آيات
                </p>
                </div>
                <div>
                <h2>Transliteration (English)</h2>
                <p xml:lang="en">
                Surah Al-Baqarah, Medinan, and it has 280 [verses].

                In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.

                Alif Lam Meem.
                This is the Book about which there is no doubt, a guidance for those who are conscious of Allah —
                Who believe in the unseen, establish prayer, and spend out of what We have provided them;
                And who believe in what has been revealed to you, and what was revealed before you, and are certain of the Hereafter.
                Those are upon guidance from their Lord, and it is they who will be successful.
                </p>
                </div>


            </div>
            
            <div>
                <figure>
                <graphic url="assets/image1.jpg" mimeType="image/jpeg"/>
                <figDesc>
                </figDesc>
                </figure>

                <div>

                <h2>Text by OCR(Kraken)</h2>
                <p xml:lang="ar">
                    النلف
                    ويَ
                    يح

                    رهوللم ولا
                    لمسُمَما
                    بزینالذللبل
                    و
                    برابرنلوعومنا مزلعل
                    الله باللطرواليدال،
                    ممصلبمايلم واللله(بق

                    الك
                    سبیلناالبلم ویکتن ولثم وبرمل
                    لم لی
                    ۵
                    ۶

                    211485
                </p>
                
                </div>

                <div>


                <h2>Fixed text</h2>
                <p xml:lang="ar">
                    بأيمانكم ومودتكم واخبرنا بحسن لكم لما في كل حين وانكم مشتاقون الى رؤيتنا كأشتياقنا 
                    الى رؤيتكم فقد اعتزينا لذلك بكم ياخوتنا في جميع 
                    شدايدنا وعمومنا من اجل ايمانكم وللان نحيا ان انتم اقمتم علي للايمان بربنا ولي شكر نستطيع 
                    ان نؤدي عنكم الى الله على كل سرور نسره في سببكم 
                    لذلك نكثر الايمان الى الله بالليل والنهار في 
                    ان نرى وجوهكم ونكمل نقيصة ايمانكم والله ابقى سيدنا يسوع المسيح ينجح سبيلنا اليكم ويكثر ودكم ويزيد فيه
                </p>

                </div>



            </div>
        </body>
    </text>

    <listBibl>
  <head>BIBLIOGRAPHY</head>
  <bibl>
    https://atharsale.com // ItemNo : 1876
    <title level="a" type="article">A Rare Quran Manuscript.
    </title>
  </bibl>
</listBibl>
</TEI>
